The radiance of the night shines through my window
but the path to immortality is long.
The Eight Views and Nine-Bend Streams are desolate.
Living beings question the miseries of the world over a jar of wine.
Forget about Nirvana and rebirth,
I will break through the waves with my own flesh and blood.
The heavens are vast, so what if I was born mediocre ?
I stare at the Dao in my moments of madness
as the storm rages just below.
I've been thinking about life and death in my dreams.
I've unsheathed my sword to ask the immortals
why the world is a-changing.
Heaven and earth reveals its poignant truths.
Swallow the Four Seas and the Eight Wastelands,
experience all the vicissitudes of life in an instant.
I will defy the light in the sky
to continue to write a new chapter for all things in the three realms of existence.
Just a thought separates mortal from immortal.
Transform your insignificant body into light.
The hardships of the journey
will temper this young man's heart.
If I become a Renegade Immortal, will I hesitate to fight the heavens ?
Renegade Immortal
Subtitles by Bonobosubs
https://discord.gg/Ceckd4pdVA
You protected me for more than 2000 years,
you...
worked hard.
I will make you the Sword Spirit of this celestial sword.
In 10 000 years,
you will become a Celestial Saint.
Central Fragment
Rain Celestial Realm
A Rain Celestial Sword appeared.
If I get it,
it will improve the strength of planet Tian Mo.
Tian Mozi
Middle stage Nirvana Scryer
Planet Tian Mo
I just don't know which Rain Celestial Sword it is...
Southwest Fragment
Rain Celestial Realm
A celestial sword ?
My beast is able to control the Sword Spirit within the sword.
Ling Tianhou
Late stage Nirvana Cleanser
Da Lou Sword Sect Leader
With it, planet Tian Yun will finally be mine.
Brother Chi Hu,
star compass !
Thanks to Brother Ceng,
we are out of danger for now.
But the star compass is still damaged.
I'm afraid it won't take us far enough to cross the void.
The star compass,
the treasure of the Giant Demon Clan.
Sadly,
it's only an imitation.
Ceng Niu,
if you agree to release the seal,
I can promise to safely return you to planet Suzaku.
How does it sound ?
I don't just have 3 souls, but a fourth one as well.
The fourth one is inside the body in the coffin.
Senior Zhou Yi never mentioned a fourth soul.
He might be lying
so let's probe him.
I'm afraid Senior's words
must have some other meaning.
Besides, you must already know
that I cannot break
the seal of an Ascendant cultivator.
Alright,
you have some guts.
No wonder you are the one Zhou Yi chose.
Now come with me right now !
The slave seal is unstable.
Use the pagoda to protect yourself.
Sun Tai,
Senior Zhou Yi specifically made this pagoda
so that it could kill you.
Zhou Yi...
I know a little bit
about your Corpse Sect.
The corpse inside the coffin
most likely contains someone else's soul.
Even if it's your fourth soul,
it's a broken soul !
I won’t lower myself to deal with a Junior like you !
Since he retreated,
the fourth soul must be a lie.
He can't take this risk.
Brother Ceng,
Sun Tai's cultivation is very high.
You have to be careful in the future.
Don't worry,
Senior Zhou Yi told me that keeping him alive
serves a greater purpose.
Otherwise I would have already killed him and his fourth soul.
I can't kill him, I can't trap him...
He's really troublesome...
It seems Zhou Yi intends to use me for something,
I have to find out what it is.
Brother Ceng,
this star compass can no longer fly.
We will have to fly on our own.
Brother Chi Hu,
you only brought one star compass ?
This treasure
was brought by my clan
when we migrated to Suzaku countless years ago.
But now that it's broken,
I’ll be punished for sure
when I get back.
Brother Chi Hu,
I won’t lie to you,
I can repair this star compass.
But the material to repair it is too precious.
If I repair it
then it must belong to me.
This...
Forget it,
if it is too difficult for Brother Chi Hu,
I’m still willing to fix it for you
as a token of our friendship.
Is what you’re saying true ?
It is true.
However, I will need this star compass for something in the future,
so when I need to borrow it, don’t reject me.
With the temperament of my clan's Elders,
there's no way they would lend it to you.
That's why
I might as well gift it to you !
Brother Ceng,
this star compass is now yours.
Thank you very much.
I will have to ask Brother Chi Hu to protect me.
According to Tu Si's memory,
a star compass is made of this material.
This Ceng Niu
has a shocking cultivation and courage.
He also obtained Zhou Yi's Ascendant Crystal.
If he becomes a true friend,
it will benefit the clan in the future.
Brother Ceng,
are you done repairing it ?
There should be no problems leaving this void.
Central Fragment
Rain Celestial Realm
Second Rain Celestial Sword,
appear !
Second Rain Celestial Sword
If the Celestial Realm was still intact,
I would just throw your soul
in the Celestial Purification Pond.
But now that it's gone, to restore your Origin Soul,
one Rain Celestial Sword
is too slow.
Ting'er,
why are you doing all of this ?
Do you want to waste the celestial spiritual energy
I have gathered for you during thousands of years ?
Zhou Yi
Sword Spirit
I refuse to let you die,
so you will not die.
And my name
is not Ting'er.
Sure...
you are not called Ting'er…
I have already remembered everything…
However,
this name, Ting'er…
I like it
very much.
They're coming.
That's...
celestial swords ?
Where are they coming from ?
Third Rain Celestial Sword
Celestial swords !
They really are celestial swords !
Ting'er,
are 3 Rain Celestial Swords not enough ?
It's not enough,
the Fourth Rain Celestial Sword will soon take form.
A celestial Qilin...
The Da Lou Sword Sect’s guardian beast !
This beast belongs to Sword Saint Ling Tianhou !
Is he...
Welcome Master.
A single glance was enough
to be injured by his sword intent.
This old man's cultivation
is terrifying.
Are you a Celestial ?
A Celestial ?!
How can this be ?
Even if she is a Celestial,
there is no way she can match Ling Tianhou.
Stand down !
The Celestial Realm has already collapsed.
If you really are a surviving Celestial,
then this old man wants to try killing a Celestial !
You evil creature,
even your ancestors back then
didn’t dare to act like this before me.
Could it be that you lost
your memory inheritance after the Celestial Realm collapsed ?
So you are a fake beast that never received an inheritance.
You remember now ?
Forget it,
the Celestial Realm is no more
so there is no point in me punishing you.
A single strike
destroyed 2 swords of the Sword Saint.
This Celestial is impressive !
So that's the power of a Celestial.
A single strike destroyed both my swords.
Not even the All-Seer could do this.
This woman is not a normal Celestial.
Could she be a Celestial King ?
I won't be able to get a celestial sword today.
Wait...
According to the celestial law,
my crime is worthy of destroying my Origin Soul.
But she didn't kill me.
It's not that she doesn’t want to kill me,
she wants to scare me away !
Celestial King,
I want to see how powerful you are !
Ting'er !
A Celestial
is only this strong ?
A death aura ?
She doesn't have much time left.
You should give me the celestial swords !
Ting'er !
Let me out of here !
If you use up all your celestial spiritual energy,
you will never wake up again !
You can't leave yet.
Sword Spirit,
go !
All-Seer,
if you keep me from taking the celestial sword,
when I get back
our sects will fight for 1000 years !
The All-Seer ?!
I am the All-Seer.
Since we met, let's make a deal.
The celestial sword belongs to those who are fated to have it.
If you can get it,
then you are fated.
Tian Mozi !
I'm not greedy.
Of the 4 celestial swords,
I’ll only take one.
Goodbye.
You dare to steal from me ?
My Da Lou Sword Sect will wipe your planet Tian Mo !
Sure, I'll be waiting for you.
You can have this sword
but the Sword Spirit is mine.
This sword belongs to me !
This celestial sword lost its Sword Spirit
so it cannot use any of its spells anymore...
Ling Tianhou,
you obtaining this sword is heavenly fate
so I won’t stop you.
But know your own limits…
You don't have much life left in you.
Since you're a Celestial,
I won't kill you.
But I will take the Sword Spirits of the remaining 2 swords !
Ting'er !
Stop !
Break for me !
Ting'er !!!
I am not the true soul of a Celestial King.
I am a remnant of a soul that was condensed somehow.
But when you ignited your Origin Soul,
I understood.
I was born out of your obsession for me…
Zhou Yi,
thank you.
If there is another life,
I hope that I’m not a remnant of a soul
and that you
will still be by my side...
Ting'er !!!
Fourth Rain Celestial Sword
Nooooo !!!
We just encountered some new cultivation levels. They will be explained later. You will find the updated cultivation level cheat sheet below.
Qi Condensation
Foundation Establishment
Core Formation
Nascent Soul
Soul Formation
Soul Transformation
Ascendant
??
Nirvana Scryer
Nirvana Cleanser
Falling from the night sky and melting into dust
like water without a source.
Like the difference between clouds and mud,
the truth cannot be found in conflict.
Life and death
are like the moment when the rain falls
and like many other unseparable things.
In this lifetime,
to cultivate the truth, cultivate the world first.
Old grudges had to be settled
because half an inch is engraved into my tree rings.
Use the most vivid love and hate
to ask questions to your fate.
Let your eyes be filled enough with rage
to pierce the heart and the soul
then soften because of the mortals' fireworks.
Only when you bend down can you understand
the hidden edge of the blade.
The human mind is nature,
the rain fell silently like an answer.
Life and death are just moments away,
there are many other solutions to grudges.
Use your dusty heart
to depict the world.
One stroke is for killing.
After struggling for hundreds of years, I endured letting go.
One stroke is for caring.
Everywhere there is life, there are thousands of lights.
Give up your mind to be refined
by this endless world.
The human mind is nature,
the rain fell silently like an answer.
Life and death are just moments away,
there are many other solutions to grudges.
Use your dusty heart
to depict the world.
One stroke is for killing.
After struggling for hundreds of years, I endured letting go.
One stroke is for caring.
Everywhere there is life, there are thousands of lights.
Give up your mind to be refined
by this endless world.
Snow falls as my hair turns white, winter withers
while prosperity sprouts in summer.
I step into the world, with light at my fingertips,
the law of cause and effect.
I observe the vastness of heaven and earth so I can get rid of evil.
Obsession arises from one thought, life and death arise from one thought.
Reincarnation is not to be feared.